About Me

Hi! My Name is **Ahmad Fikri Mudzaki** you can call me Eki, I am Full Stack QA Engineer

I'm passionate with QA field with more than 10 years experiences. I really like to have challenges. Moreover, I could participate effectively in a team or work individually. I'm very adaptable with any job environment and also having many experience on testing field, it's pleasure to learn and work with brand new technologies.

You can find My GitHub

Experiences

Senior QA ENGINEER - WorlderGroup(Mar 2023 - Present)

- Responsible to evaluate SDLC in the company and standarized QA process in the team.
- Improve the way the team testing and help developer and stackholder.
- Manage 2 teams to follow standarized process that company agreed to follow.
- Impement API testing using Postman newman and integrate it with Jenkins (CI/CD).

LEAD QA ENGINEER - Gojek(Feb 2017 - Nov 2022)

- Responsible to standardized QA process in MOKA Android by following company standard. Responsibe to maintain and optimize automated framework to cover 100% automatable cases using JAVA, RESTAssured for API automated test, Gitlab, BrowserStack as cloud testing, Spring, Appium
- Leading 2 teams with two different product. Lead Merchant Platform, customize and improve automated framework, Enabling automated test on special device(POS EDC), create and maintain runner to be able to run it on EDC device and integrate it with CI/CD (Gitlab).
- Responsible to do Full Test Cycle for Go-Send, maintain TestCases for Go-Send, Test API services using Postman. Sanity Check for old Android version, Sometimes become speaker for QA meetup.

Senior QA ENGINEER - Tokopedia(Sep 2016 - Jan 2017)

• Responsible to maintain automation TestCases for mobile app, fixing and adding feature on automation framework (using java and php).

...many more

Skills & Tools

- OS (Mac, Windows, Linux)
- Vitualization (docker)
- CI/CD (gitlab, jenkins)
- Language (Java, JavaScript, Ruby)
- API testing (Postman, Newman, RestAssured, HttpToolkit, Charles Proxy, Flipper, Etc)
- Functional Automated testing (Selenium, Appium, SeleniumGrid, Cucumber)
- Manual testing (Web, Mobile)
- Agile tools (JIRA, Trello)
- Documentation (GDocs, Confuence)

Projects

Trainer - Quality Engineering for Astra Honda Motor x Kodehive (Dec 2022)

- Basic knowledge QA
- Java for QA
- Create Framework using Spring, Selenium, SeleniumGrid, cucumber
- Parallel test using SeleniumGrid docker
- Integration with Jenkins

Trainer - Sharing session about QA x University of Indonesia (2021)

- Introduction to QA
- Daily task as QA Engineer
- How to start become QA Engineer
- Freelancing as QA Engineer

Speaker - Sharing session about QA x ISQA (2018)

- What we do in Gojek
- Share about Appium Ruby Console arc GitHub

Certification

[1] iSQI GmbH, License 15-CMAPFL-TE-80220-31

Education

(2013 - 2016) BACHELOR DEGREE IN IT ENGINEERING UNIVERSITAS MERCUBUANA

(2009-2012) ASSOCIATE DEGREE IN INFORMATICS IT TELKOM, BANDUNG

Page design by Ankit Sultana